Guide to the Lifwynn Foundation Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Lifwynn Foundation records
1924-1995
MS 1681
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
42.25
The records consist of the Lifwynn Foundation's correspondence, organizational files, research data, financial records, and copies of the foundation's publication, Lifwynn Correspondenc e, which provides a forum for scholars interested in exploring the nature of contemporary social neurosis. Also included in the records are materials from the files of Clarence Shields, William E. Galt, and Charles B. Thompson.
Lifwynn Foundation
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the Lifwynn Foundation, 1995 and 1999.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials in box 25 of Accession 1999-M-082 are closed for seventy-five years from the date of creation, 2026-2064.
Associated Materials
Related material: Trigant Burrow Papers (MS 1370). Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.
Related material: Hans Syz Papers (MS 1624). Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.
Biographical / Historical
The Lifwynn Foundation for Laboratory Research in Analytic and Social Psychiatry was established in 1927 to provide an institutional setting for the pioneer group research originated by Trigant Burrow. Burrow established an experimental community to investigate the pathology of "normality," and the investigators were included as elements in the social fabric to be observed. In addition to Burrow, the Lifwynn Foundation founders included Hans Syz and Clarence Shields.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of the Lifwynn Foundation's correspondence, organizational files, research data, financial records, and copies of the foundation's publication, Lifwynn Correspondence, which provides a forum for scholars interested in exploring the nature of contemporary social neurosis. Also included in the records are materials from the files of Clarence Shields, William E. Galt, and Charles B. Thompson.
Psychology; Social psychology; Burrow, Trigant, 1875-1950; Galt, William Egleston, 1904-1955; Syz, Hans C.; Thompson, Charles B.; Lifwynn Foundation
- Original accession, 1990-1994; Accession 1995-M-102; 0.25
  - Lifwynn Correspondence, vols. 1-2, 1990-1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Lifwynn Correspondence, vol. 3, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Additional material, Accession 1996-M-059
  - Correspondence files, 1927-1950
    - Miscellaneous foundation (Box 1)
    - Allen, W. W. (Box 1)
    - American Association for the Advancement of Science (Box 1)
    - American Express Company (Box 1)
    - American Journal of Orthopsychiatry (Box 1)
    - American Journal of Sociology (Box 1)
    - American Medical Association (Box 1)
    - American Psychiatric Association (Box 1)
    - American Psychoanalytic Association (Box 1)
    - American Psychological Association (Box 1)
    - American Psychopathological Association (Box 1)
    - American Sociological Review (Box 1)
    - American Sociological Society (Box 1)
    - American L - An (Box 1)
    - Applications for positions (Box 1)
    - Australian Psychology Centre (Box 1)
    - Automobile (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous A (Box 1)
    - Barton, Randolph (Box 1)
    - Base Management Unit (Box 1)
    - Beacon (Box 1)
    - Bispham, Mr. and Mrs. George Tucker (Box 1)
    - Bispham, Mr. and Mrs. Tucker (Box 1)
    - Blum, Miss Bessie M. (Box 1)
    - Bowery Savings Bank (Box 1)
    - Braziers Park School (Box 1)
    - Bredow, Miss M. M. (Box 1)
    - Bridgeport Herald (Box 1)
    - Bridgeport Post (Box 1)
    - Brown, Wheelock, Harris, Vought and Co. (Box 1)
    - Brown University (Box 1)
    - Bruce, E. Skipwith (Box 1)
    - Burrow, Mrs. Trigant (Box 1)
    - Burrow, Emily S. (Box 1)
    - Burrow, Mr. and Mrs. John D. (Box 1)
    - Burrow, Trigant (Box 1)
    - Mrs. Burrow - Financial, Pre-1950 (Box 1)
    - Burrow, Trigant Dr. (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous B (Box 1)
    - Cantor, Eddie (Box 1)
    - College Standard Dictionary (Box 1)
    - Columbia University Press (Box 1)
    - Commonwealth Fund (Box 1)
    - Cotention: excerpts from Dr. Burrow's writings (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous C (Box 1)
    - Dawson material (Box 1)
    - Diethelm, Oskar (Box 1)
    - Drucker, George and Estelle (Box 1)
    - Dudley, Pendleton (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous D (Box 1)
    - Einstein, Albert (Box 1)
    - Eliot, Thomas D. (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous E (Box 1)
    - Finance Committee (Box 1)
    - Financial matters (Box 1)
    - Fletcher and Brown (Box 1)
    - Ford Foundation (Box 1)
    - Freud, Sigmund, Archives, Inc. (Box 1)
    - Fritchey, Ethel M. (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous F (Box 1)
    - Galt, William E. (Box 2)
    - General Systems (Box 2)
    - Gilden, Lloyd (Box 2)
    - Gregg, Alan (Box 2)
    - Greiner, S. (Box 2)
    - Guggenheimer, F. A. (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous G (Box 2)
    - Harcourt, Brace and Company (Box 2)
    - Hart, Andrew E. (Box 2)
    - Holljes, Nelly (Box 2)
    - Howenstein, Karl (Box 2)
    - Huiskamp, Henry W. and Family (Box 2)
    - Huiskamp, John E. (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous H (Box 2)
    - Irving Trust Company (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous I (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous J (Box 2)
    - Kinder, Elaine F. (Box 2)
    - Korzybski, Alfred (Box 2)
    - Krishnamurti Foundation (Box 2)
    - Kronick, Harry (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous K (Box 2)
    - La Dame, Mary (Box 2)
    - LaGarde, Major and Mrs. R. D. (Box 2)
    - Lease (Box 2)
    - Leigh, Mr. and Mrs. John R. (Box 2)
    - Library of Congress (Box 2)
    - Lillie, Ralph S. (Box 2)
    - Locke, Agnes C. (Box 2)
    - Loomis, Sayles and Company (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous L (Box 2)
    - Macmillan Company (Box 2)
    - Macy, Josiah, Foundation (Box 2)
    - Malone, Mrs. Dana (Box 2)
    - Mann, Thomas (Box 2)
    - Markle, John and Mary R., Foundation (Box 2)
    - Mayne, Robert (Box 2)
    - Mayo Clinic (Box 2)
    - Mental Health (Box 2)
    - Mercantile Trust Co. (Box 2)
    - Meyer, Adolf (Box 2)
    - Moore, Mary M. (Box 2)
    - Morton, Arthur F. and Company (Box 2)
    - Murphy, Gardner (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous M (Box 2)
    - Nagel, Hildegard (Box 2)
    - National Committee for Mental Hygiene (Box 2)
    - National Cyclopedia of American Biography (Box 2)
    - National Society for Medical Research (Box 2)
    - New York Community Trust Fund (Box 2)
    - New York Herald-Tribune (Box 2)
    - The New York Public Library (Box 2)
    - New York Telephone Co. (Box 2)
    - New York Times (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous N (Box 2)
    - Office (Box 2)
    - Organization Committee (Box 2)
    - Pease, Miss Helen L. (Box 2)
    - Peavey, S. F., Jr. (Box 2)
    - Publicity (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous P (Box 2)
    - Raymond Rich Associates (Box 3)
    - Read, Herbert (Box 3)
    - Research Station: subsidiary Lifwynn Camp (Box 3)
    - Romeike, Henry, Inc. (Box 3)
    - Rosenburg, Max: diary of Hopi Anthropological Survey (Box 3)
    - Rowland, Harold (Box 3)
    - Royalties from all publications (Box 3)
    - Russell Sage Foundation (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous R (Box 3)
    - Sanger, Margaret (Box 3)
    - Schlesinger, H. S. (Box 3)
    - Schroeder, Johanna (Box 3)
    - Shields, Clarence (Box 3)
    - Sien Tu (Box 3)
    - Sill, Alfreda (Box 3)
    - Sill, Misses (Box 3)
    - Smithwick, Graham (Box 3)
    - Social Science Research Council (Box 3)
    - Social Work Year Book (Box 3)
    - Sorokin, Pitirim (Box 3)
    - Stein, Leo (Box 3)
    - Surrogate Court (Box 3)
    - Syz, Anthony (Box 3)
    - Syz, Hans (Box 3)
    - Syz, Mrs. Hans (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous S (Box 3)
    - Sale of publications, unpaid bills, book notices (Box 3)
    - Tax reports and correspondence (Box 3)
    - Taxes, withholding (Box 3)
    - Thayer, Ellen and Lucy (Box 3)
    - Thompson, Charles B. (Box 3)
    - Twentieth Century Fund (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous T (Box 3)
    - Ulman, Judge and Mrs. Joseph N. (Box 3)
    - U.S. Public Health Service (Box 3)
    - Université Libre de Bruxelles (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous U (Box 3)
    - Vaillant, Dr. and Mrs. Rene (Box 3)
    - Virginia, University of (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous V (Box 3)
    - Wallace, Kevin (Box 3)
    - Watson, Goodwin B. (Box 3)
    - Wechsler, E. B. (Box 3)
    - Wells, H. G. (Box 3)
    - Westport Bank and Trust Company (Box 3)
    - Whyte, Lancelot Law (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous W (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous XYZ (Box 3)
  - Office Files
    - Incoming mail, 1932-1950 (Box 4)
    - Diary of daily events, 1932-1950 (Box 4)
    - Office routine (Box 4)
    - Staff meeting minutes, 1947-1950 (Box 4)
    - Appointment books for Group Meetings, 1928-1931 (Box 4)
    - Account book
      General note
      See: Box 13
    - Concordance of The Neurosis of Man [used during preparation of the manuscript] (Box 4)
  - Galt, William E. [primarily writings], circa 1943-1953 (Box 4)
  - Thompson, Charles B. [correspondence, notes, drafts], Circa 1929-1957 (Box 4)
  - Shields, Clarence [correspondence, drafts, notes, reference material, estate papers], Circa 1929-1951 (Box 5)
  - Instrumental File [raw data, experimental protocols, reports, correspondence], Circa 1937-1956
    - A misc. (Box 6)
    - Basal metabolism (Box 6)
    - B misc. (Box 6)
    - Catalogs (Box 6)
    - C misc. (Box 6)
    - Drugs (Box 6)
    - D misc. (Box 6)
    - Electroencephalography (Box 6)
    - Electrocardiogram (Box 6)
    - Experimentation (Box 6)
    - Eye movement camera and eye movements (Box 6)
    - Eye movements (Box 7)
    - Foundation ophthalmograph (Box 7)
    - Graphs (Box 7)
    - G-H misc. (Box 7)
    - Instrumentation (Box 7)
    - J misc. (Box 7)
    - Kymograph (Box 7)
    - K misc. (Box 7)
    - Lab experiments (Box 7)
    - L misc. (Box 7)
    - Motion pictures (Box 7)
    - Muscular action currents (Box 7)
    - Muscular tension (Box 7)
    - M-O misc. (Box 7)
    - Physiological aspects (Box 7)
    - P misc. (Box 7)
    - Respiration (kymograph) (Box 7)
    - Rmisc. (Box 7)
    - Shields, Clarence (Box 7)
    - Sill, Mrs. H. A. (Box 7)
    - Stylograph paper (Box 7)
    - Syz, Mrs Hans; Burrow, John D. (Box 7)
    - S misc. (Box 7)
    - Tensional patterns (Box 7)
    - Thompson, Charles B. (Box 7)
    - T misc. (Box 7)
    - Various projects (Box 7)
    - V-Z misc. (Box 7)
    - Films (Box 7)
  - Corporate File
    - Committee on By-Laws, 1929-1930 (Box 8)
    - Organization Committee, 1928-1930 (Box 8)
    - Announcement material, 1930 (Box 8)
    - Budget material and budget, 1934-1950 (Box 8)
    - Agendas for annual meetings, 1929-1950 (Box 8)
    - Minute books (Box 8)
    - Vols. I-VII, 1927-1941 (Box 8)
    - Vols. VIII-XV, 1942-1973 (Box 9)
  - Financial
    - Reports by independent auditors, 1928-1950 (Box 10)
    - Lifwynn Camp account books, 1932-1953 (Box 10)
    - Journals and cash disbursements records, 1928-1951- (Box 11–12)
  - Account book [monthly records of payments from students in group work and from Burrow's private patients], 1924, 1927-1928 (Box 13)
- Additional material, Accession 1999-M-082
  Conditions Governing Access
  Materials in box 25 are restricted for seventy-five years from the date of creation (1950-1988), and will be available for research between 2026 and 2064.
  - A. G. Edwards & Sons, Inc. (Box 1)
  - Christopher Aanstoos (Box 1)
  - Nathan W. Ackerman (Box 1)
  - Acta Psychotherapeutica et Psychosomatica (Box 1)
  - AHP Newsletter (Box 1)
  - Alcohol Permit Material (Box 1)
  - American "A" - American "Y" (Box 1)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science (Box 1)
  - American Psychiatric Association (Box 1)
  - American Psychoanalytic Association (Box 1)
  - American Psychological Association (Box 1)
  - American Psychopathological Association (Box 1)
  - American Joumal of Psychiatry (Box 1)
  - Sperry Andrews (Box 1)
  - Archives of the History of American Psychology (Box 1)
  - Professor U. A. Asrani (Box 1)
  - Association for Humanistic Psychology, 1962-1989 (Box 1)
  - Association for Humanistic Psychology-Silver Spring Meetings, 1969 August (Box 1)
  - Lee Aubrey (Box 1)
  - Australian Psychology Center (Box 1)
  - A-Az (Box 1)
  - Dr. Nancy Baker (Box 1)
  - Dr. Harry Elmer Barnes (Box 1)
  - Hank Barru (Box 1)
  - Basic Books-Publicity & Promotion (Box 1)
  - Basic Books-Material on Index-- Preconscious Foundations (Box 1)
  - Daniel Bassuk (Box 1)
  - Beacon Press (Box 1)
  - Jim Bebout (Box 1)
  - Dr. Elizabeth Behnke, 1985-1993 (Box 1)
  - Ted Beimler, 1955-1993 (Box 2)
  - Benson/Quinlan Insurance Agency (Box 2)
  - Mrs. Frank Berkowitz (Bess) (Box 2)
  - Dr. Leo Berman (Box 2)
  - Gerald Berton (Box 2)
  - "Beyond War" (Box 2)
  - Shri K. L. Bhola (Box 2)
  - Goddard Binkley (Box 2)
  - Dr. & Mrs. Kingsley Birge (Box 2)
  - Dr. Robert Blake (Box 2)
  - Dr. David Bohm (Box 2)
  - Book Dealers-European (Box 2)
  - Books on Hand (Box 2)
  - Book Orders (Box 2)
  - John Briggs (Box 2)
  - Mary Eleanor Brown, 1967-1991 (Box 2)
  - Ilse Bry (Box 3)
  - Nina Bull, 1952-1967 (Box 3)
  - Robert J. Burdett (Box 3)
  - Dr. Guy Bumeko (Box 3)
  - John C. Burnham (Box 3)
  - Stanley Bumshaw (Box 3)
  - Mr. & Mrs. John D. Burrow (Box 3)
  - Mrs. Trigant Burrow (Box 3)
  - Mrs. Burrow--Societies (Box 3)
  - Biographical Material on Trigant Burrow (Box 3)
  - Biography-Dr. Burrow (Box 3)
  - Dr. Burrow-Biographical Data--A-Z (Box 3)
  - Burrow Collection (Box 3)
  - Burrow Papers-Library Mailing, 1989 (Box 3)
  - Mailing of TB's Papers to Universities (Box 3)
  - Comments on Dr. Burrow's Writing w/ ASG-Comments (Box 3)
  - Paper Backs--Dr. Burrow's Books (Box 3)
  - Dr. Burrow-List of College Libraries Offered Reprints (Box 3)
  - B -Bz (Box 3)
  - Calendar-Foundation Monthly Reminders (Box 3)
  - Camp, 1989 (Box 3)
  - Juan and Hanne Campos (Box 3)
  - Dr. Eric Carlson (Box 3)
  - F. L. Cawthon, 1959-1992 (Box 3)
  - Center for the Advancement of Human Communication-Fairfield Univ. (Box 4)
  - City National Bank (Box 4)
  - City Trust Co.-Charles B. Thompson (Box 4)
  - City Trust Co., 1959-1974 (Box 4)
  - George W. Clark, 1972-1990 (Box 4)
  - David E. Clarke (Box 4)
  - College of Physicians of Philadelphia (Box 4)
  - Conference on Addiction, 1990 (Box 4)
  - Conference-Chicago, 1988 December (Box 4)
  - Conference, 1988 October (Box 4)
  - Connecticut National Bank (CNB) (Box 4)
  - Hartford National Bank (CNB) (Box 4)
  - Connecticut (State of) (Box 4)
  - Consciousness (Box 4)
  - Copyrights (Box 4)
  - Dr. Joseph Couture (Box 4)
  - Dr. Martha Crampton (Box 4)
  - Dr. Richard Crocket (Box 4)
  - Ivan Crow (Box 4)
  - Dr. Ralph M. Crowley (Box 4)
  - C-Cop (Box 4)
  - Cor-Cz (Box 5)
  - Eugene W. Dawson (Box 5)
  - Rodney Dennehy (Box 5)
  - Dr. Prakash Desai (Box 5)
  - Dr. Oskar Diethelm (Box 5)
  - Directories (Box 5)
  - Dream Workshops (Box 5)
  - George & Estelle Drucker (Box 5)
  - Dr. Pendleton Dudley (Box 5)
  - John E. Dufford (Sulaiman) (Box 5)
  - Dr. Helen E. Durkin (Box 5)
  - Joan Dydo-Pate Institute (Box 5)
  - D-Dz (Box 5)
  - Maurice C. Edwards (Box 5)
  - George F. Egleston (Box 5)
  - Dr. Moses L. Ehrlich (Box 5)
  - Electrophysiology (Box 5)
  - Professor Thomas D. Eliot (Box 5)
  - Harold Ellis (Box 5)
  - Alfred Emerson (Box 5)
  - Esalen Institute (Box 5)
  - Experimental Equipment (Box 5)
  - Experimental Program-Notes, 1964-1969 (Box 5)
  - Experimentation--Misc. (Box 5)
  - Exposition Press, 1951-1959 (Box 5)
  - Eye-Movement Camera (S.l.) (Box 5)
  - E -Ez (Box 6)
  - Fairfield County Estate Liquidation Inc. (Box 6)
  - Dr. Lester Fehmi (Box 6)
  - Allan B. Feinstein (Box 6)
  - Final Determination (Box 6)
  - Moshe Felderikrais (Box 6)
  - Georg Feuerstein (Box 6)
  - Financial Matters (Box 6)
  - Mrs. H. Whitney Fish (Edith) (Box 6)
  - George Fisher (Box 6)
  - The Ford Foundation (Box 6)
  - Foreign Psychologists & Psychiatrists (a draft letter to) (Box 6)
  - Form Letters-Acknowledgments (Box 6)
  - Foundations-Information (Box 6)
  - Foundation for Integrated Education, Inc. (Box 6)
  - Dr. Frederick Franck (Box 6)
  - Dr. Jerome D. Frank (Box 6)
  - J. Stuart Franklin (Box 6)
  - The Free Press (Box 6)
  - Freud-The Sigmund Freud Archives, Inc. (Box 6)
  - Michelle Fromme (Box 6)
  - F - Fz (Box 6)
  - Dr. Iago Galdstone, 1957-1985 (Box 6)
  - Review of Galen (On the Passions & Errors of the Soul-H.S.) (Box 6)
  - Mrs. William E. Galt (Box 6)
  - Alfreda S. Galt, "An Altered Approach to Insanity" (Box 6)
  - Alfreda S. Galt, "Therapy in Context of Trigant Burrow's Group Analysis" (Box 6)
  - Dr. William E. Galt, 1952-1955 (Box 6)
  - International Jean Gebser Society (Box 6)
  - Jean Gebser Studies (Box 6)
  - Henry Geiger, 1953-1989 (Box 6)
  - Professor Iris G. Gelletti-(Ciarpella), 1968-1977 (Box 7)
  - Gelletti Manuscript (Box 7)
  - Dr. Eugene Gendlin (Box 7)
  - Society for General Systems Research (Box 7)
  - Dr. Ralph W. Gerard (Box 7)
  - Dr. Albin R. Gilbert (Box 7)
  - Dr. Lloyd Gilden, 1951-1991 (Box 7)
  - Dr. Kurt Goldstein (Box 7)
  - Dr. Judith Gordon (Box 7)
  - Dr. John Goyeche (Box 7)
  - Dr. Charles C. Graves (Box 7)
  - Dr. William Gray (Box 7)
  - Great Barrington (Box 7)
  - Maurice Greenbaum, 1961-1990 (Box 7)
  - Tom Greening (Box 7)
  - Dr. Alan Gregg (Box 7)
  - Joan Grene, 1967-1991 (Box 7)
  - Group Psychotherapy - Jacob L. Moreno (Box 7)
  - Grone & Stratton, Inc. (Box 7)
  - Aimee Guggenheimer, 1936-1964 (Box 7)
  - Aimee Guggenheimer-Estate of (Box 7)
  - Sidney Guimaraes, 1971-1991 (Box 7)
  - Ga-Gq (Box 7)
  - Gr- Gz (Box 8)
  - Hall Brooke Foundation (Box 8)
  - Richard D. Halverson (Box 8)
  - Tom Hanna (Box 8)
  - John A. Hannum (Box 8)
  - Harris, Kerr Forster, 1928-1978 (Box 8)
  - Dr. Joseph Hart (Box 8)
  - Philip M. Heggen (Box 8)
  - Dr. Martha Herbert (Box 8)
  - Louis Herbst (Box 8)
  - Professor C. Judson Herrick (Box 8)
  - Andrew Hilgartner (Box 8)
  - Dr. Deborah Hillman (Box 8)
  - Hillman Papers (Box 8)
  - George Hiltebeitel (Box 8)
  - Jack Himmelstein (Box 8)
  - Hinkley & Singley (Box 8)
  - Gerhard Hirschfeld, 1954-1975 (Box 8)
  - Maggie Hodgson (Box 8)
  - Yushi Honde (Box 8)
  - Horizon Press, 1981-1987 (Box 8)
  - Mr. and Mrs. Karl Howenstein (Box 8)
  - Mrs. Frances Hubbell (Box 8)
  - Dr. Toby E. Huff (Box 8)
  - The Humanist "Conflict and Social Mood"-Alfreda S. Galt (Box 8)
  - Dr. Edward Humphreys, 1951-1992 (Box 9)
  - Humpreys Paper (Box 9)
  - Ralph & Christa Hurttlen, 1968-1992 (Box 9)
  - H-Hz (Box 9)
  - International Association of Group Psychotherapy-Bookseller (Box 9)
  - ICY Conference (Box 9)
  - Institute of General Semantics, 1950-1992 (Box 9)
  - Institute of Noetic Sciences (Box 10)
  - Institute for Study ofHuman Knowledge (Box 10)
  - Inter-Library Loans (Box 10)
  - International Journal of Social Psychiatry (Box 10)
  - Iron Mountain Storage (Box 10)
  - Irving Trust Co. (Box 10)
  - I- Iz (Box 10)
  - Dennis Jackson- D.H. Lawrence Review (Box 10)
  - Dr. Thomas H. Jobe (Box 10)
  - Dr. Avery Johnson (Box 10)
  - Dr. Don Johnson (Box 10)
  - Charles Jones (Box 10)
  - Perry Jones (Box 10)
  - Robert E. Jones (Box 10)
  - Journals, List of Bound (Box 10)
  - Journals (Box 10)
  - J - Jz (Box 10)
  - S. Karger AG (Box 10)
  - Richard Kamette (Box 10)
  - Betty Keane (Box 10)
  - Dr. Stanley Keleman (Box 10)
  - Dr. Tina Keller - Jenny (Box 10)
  - Recollections of My Encounter With Dr. Jung by Tina Keller (Box 10)
  - Dr. Harold Kelman (Box 10)
  - Ed Klinge (Box 10)
  - Ed Klinge Manuscript (Box 10)
  - Bob Knighton, 1970-1992 (Box 10)
  - Alfred A. Knopf Inc. (Box 10)
  - Lester Kobiemicki (Box 10)
  - Alice Koller (Box 11)
  - Ray Kozakiewicz (Box 11)
  - Krishnamurti Foundation (Box 11)
  - K-Kz (Box 11)
  - Dr. Wallace L. LaBaw (Box 11)
  - Mrs. Beata LaGarde (Box 11)
  - Major R. D. and Mrs. LaGarde, 1928-1992 (Box 11)
  - Mrs. A. K. Larsen (Box 11)
  - Dr. Paul Leroy Latham (Box 11)
  - D. H. Lawrence (Box 11)
  - Dr. Linda Leonard (Box 11)
  - Library Assistant (Box 11)
  - Library of Congress (Box 11)
  - Dr. E. James Liebennan (Box 11)
  - Lifwynn Camp-Research Station (Box 11)
  - The Lifwynn Foundation-Members (Box 11)
  - Lifwynn Foundation-House & Grounds (Box 11)
  - Dr. Thomas S. Langner (Box 11)
  - J. D. Lawrence (Box 11)
  - Little, Brown & Company (Box 11)
  - Livraria Itatiaia Ltda. (Box 11)
  - Dr. Nonnan Locke (Box 11)
  - Loomis-Sayles & Company (Box 11)
  - Alexander Luncan (Box 11)
  - Lunch Meeting Reports, 1966-1968 (Box 11)
  - Dr. Alberto Lyra (Box 11)
  - L-Lz (Box 11)
  - Fraser MacIver (Box 11)
  - S. Maehara (Japan) (Box 11)
  - Mrs. Dana Malone (Marg. Bradford) (Box 12)
  - Donald McA. Manson (Box 12)
  - Galen Marburg (Box 12)
  - Dr. Rollo May (Box 12)
  - Robert Mayne (Box 12)
  - Dr. Karl Menninger (Box 12)
  - Menninger Clinic (Box 12)
  - Dr. Bjorn Merker, 1967-1992 (Box 12)
  - Bjorn Merker-Reports (Box 12)
  - Claire Merrill (Box 12)
  - Mrs. Nicholas B. Merryman (Virginia) (Box 12)
  - Dr. Donald Michael (Box 12)
  - Microfilming (Box 12)
  - Microfilms-List of Libraries Offered the Microfilms (Box 12)
  - Microfilms-Correspondence and Acknowledgments (Foreign & Domestic) (Box 12)
  - Microfilms-Permission Received (Box 12)
  - Microfilms-Requests--Foreign & Domestic (Box 12)
  - Toshiro Mikami (Box 12)
  - Russell Miles (Box 12)
  - Dr. Shile K. Mitra (Box 12)
  - Professor M. F. Ashley-Montagu (Box 12)
  - Lloyd & Mary Morain (Box 12)
  - Dr. J. L. Moreno (Box 12)
  - Arthur Morgan School (Box 12)
  - Mary M. Moore (Box 12)
  - Frances J. Mott (Box 12)
  - H. W. Mudry (Box 12)
  - Dr. Hugh Mullan (Box 12)
  - Professor Gardner Murphy (Box 12)
  - Mrs. Cannen McBean/Becker (Box 12)
  - McGraw Hill Book Co. (Box 12)
  - Chico McKay (Box 12)
  - Boyd McKeon (Box 12)
  - Bud McKeon (Box 12)
  - M-Mz (Box 13)
  - Mc (Box 13)
  - Professor Yoshihiro Nakanishi (Box 13)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities (Box 13)
  - National Science Foundation (Box 13)
  - National Society for Medical Research (Box 13)
  - Edward Nehls (Box 13)
  - Dr. John R. Neill (Box 13)
  - Neurosis of Man Promotion Ideas (NOM) (Box 13)
  - NOM -Acknowledgment of Portuguese Library (Box 13)
  - NOM -Snaps (Box 13)
  - New York Academy of Medicine (Box 13)
  - New York Times (Box 13)
  - David Nyberg (Box 13)
  - N-Nz (Box 14)
  - John Ohliger (Box 14)
  - Oskar Diethelm Historical Library (Box 14)
  - Our Common Neurosis (Box 14)
  - Oxford University Press (Box 14)
  - Dr. Kenji Ohtsuki-Tokyo Institute of Psychoanalysis (Box 14)
  - Dr. Glenn A. Olds (Box 14)
  - Dr. Paul Olsen (Box 14)
  - Mrs. And Mrs. Charles O'Neill (Box 14)
  - Dr. Marvin Opler (Box 14)
  - O-Oz (Box 14)
  - Irina Pabst (Box 14)
  - Dr. Harry Panjwani (Box 14)
  - Pannell Kerr Forster (Box 14)
  - Dr. Buryl Payne (Box 14)
  - Dr. William L. Peltz (Box 14)
  - People Encouraging People Inc. (Box 14)
  - People's Savings Bank (Box 14)
  - Maria Rita F. Pereira (Box 14)
  - Permission Received for the Anthology (Box 14)
  - Permission Preconscious Foundations (Box 14)
  - Mrs. E. G. Perry (Box 14)
  - Phenomenology & Psychiatry, Society of (Box 14)
  - Philosophical Library (Box 14)
  - Photos (Box 14)
  - Phyloanalysis (Box 14)
  - Dr. Claude Pigott, 1976-1985 (Box 14)
  - Dr. Malcolm Pines (Box 14)
  - Dr. Arthur Upham Pope (Box 14)
  - Portuguese Version of Neurosis of Man (Box 14)
  - Postgraduate Center for Mental Health (Box 14)
  - Preconscious Foundations of Human Experience (Box 14)
  - Preconscious Foundations -Miscellaneous (Box 14)
  - Dr. Raymond Prince (Box 14)
  - Dr. Ira Progoff (Box 14)
  - Projects (Box 15)
  - P - pz (Box 15)
  - Queens College (Box 15)
  - Questionnaires, 1970-1987 (Box 15)
  - Q (Box 15)
  - Charlotte Read, 1966-1987 (Box 15)
  - Herbert Read (Box 15)
  - Reader, 1974-1979 (Box 15)
  - Comments on Reader, 1978-1979 (Box 15)
  - Reader Originals and Copies (Box 15)
  - Reader Reflections Material (Box 15)
  - Mrs. John B. Reilly (Margie) (Box 15)
  - Research and Publications-Correspondence (Box 15)